<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Electronic Lab Notebook</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Electronic Lab Notebook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>eunise.aquino@connect.qut.edu.au (Martha Aquino)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>eunise.aquino@connect.qut.edu.au (Martha Aquino)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2018 -- All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding outliers in quantitative data</title>
      <link>/posts/finding-outliers-in-quantitative-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>eunise.aquino@connect.qut.edu.au (Martha Aquino)</author>
      <guid>/posts/finding-outliers-in-quantitative-data/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionFinding outliers in a dataset help identify any non-sense data that may not be obvious from the histograms. If they are not non-sense, they may be present due to measurement variability or it may indicate an error. Regardless, it is important to identify outliers as they can significantly affect the results of subsequent statistical analyses and it may be necessary to exclude them from the dataset prior to data imputation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plotting histograms for quantitative phenotypic data</title>
      <link>/posts/plotting-histograms-for-quantitative-phenotypic-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>eunise.aquino@connect.qut.edu.au (Martha Aquino)</author>
      <guid>/posts/plotting-histograms-for-quantitative-phenotypic-data/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionHistograms show the frequency distribution of continuous data. It can also be used to inspect whether the data is normally distributed, skewed, and indicate the presence of outliers or non-sense data. The continuous data is split into intervals called bins, and the frequency of scores that fit within each bin is recorded and plotted. Since the data is continuous, histograms are plotted with no spaces in between each bar. (https://statistics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cleaning phenotypic data</title>
      <link>/posts/cleaning-phenotypic-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>eunise.aquino@connect.qut.edu.au (Martha Aquino)</author>
      <guid>/posts/cleaning-phenotypic-data/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionThe phenotypic data collected from the eye examinations in 2008 were collated in a single excel file. The file contains data from all 801 study participants, including their demographic, environmental, and quantitative phenotypic data. There are also comments on clinical observations. Prior to analysing the phenotypic data, it is important to identify any missing or non-sense data so as not to interfere with the analyses or its results.
AimTo identify missing and non-sense data from the phenotypic dataset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About this electronic notebook</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>eunise.aquino@connect.qut.edu.au (Martha Aquino)</author>
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>This is a simple example of setting up an electronic lab notebook using blogdown and the static site generator hugo.
The theme used it this example is a slightly modified version of temple, which is a minimal, distraction free theme suitable for electronic notebooking (in my opinion). If interested, you can find a large list of hugo themes here: https://themes.gohugo.io/
The overall setup here involves each notebook entry (post) to be assigned at least one category, i.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>